(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T16:49:28.068728",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
扉の向こうを繋いで 生まれたはずの世界は
The world born by connecting beyond the door
思いよりずっと難しくて 夢がこぼれた
was much harder than I thought, and dreams spilled over.
伝えたいことなんて いくつもあるはずないから
There can't possibly be so many things I want to say,
儚く脆い僕の声は かすれて揺れていた
so my fleeting, fragile voice was hoarse and trembling.
三度目のなんとことだって 続ける意味を探して
Looking for a meaning to keep going, even for the third time,
見たかったんだ旅の先 これでいいとよかったとそう言えるまで
until I can finally say "this is fine, I'm glad" at the end of the journey I wanted to see.
このまま終われば誰かの未来として消費されていくのだろうか
If it ends like this, will it be consumed as someone else's future?
ずっと後悔ばかり思い出す日々を笑って未だ
Still smiling through the days where I only remember regrets.
そんな悲しい顔をしないで きっと間違ってないから
Don't make such a sad face, surely it's not a mistake—
間違いになんて絶対にしないよ
I will never let it become a mistake.
すれ違いの1つ2つだって気にしないように過ごしてた
I spent my days trying not to mind a disagreement or two,
愛しさが宿ったこの体を愛してたから
because I loved this body where love resided.
何者にもなれなくて もがき続けた時間ごと
Along with the time I struggled without becoming anyone,
交代できるか分からない 分からないけど
I wonder if I can replace it... I don't know, but—
辛ければ辛いほど 笑い話にもなるでしょ
The harder it is, the more it'll become a funny story, right?
君の声だって聞こえるから
Because I can hear your voice,
大丈夫だよ 大丈夫だよ
it'll be okay, it'll be okay.
最高な日も 最悪な日も 音楽とともに
The best days and the worst days alike, together with music.
降り注いだ冷たい雨
The ice-cold raindrops falling from the sky
青い傷を溶かしてた。
melted away all my blue scars.
いつか見てた夕暮れ空の
In the corner of the twilight sky I used to see,
すみっこで笑う誰かがいた。
there was someone smiling.
気付かないうちにオトナになって
Before I knew it, I grew up into an adult,
綺麗な嘘口に出出来るほど
able to let out such beautiful lies,
いろんな痛みを覚えてきたけど
and though I've learned of so many different pains,
それでもまだ痛いんだ。
it still hurts inside.
夕暮れの涙が出そうな赤
The glowing red of twilight that brings tears to my eyes
私の中の君を溶かしてしまえ。
will melt away the you inside of me.
私の体中君の傷跡で
My body is overflowing with your scars,
溢れているからもう進めないよ。
so I can't take another step.
ねぇ 消して 消してよ
Hey, make it disappear, make it go away—
そう願っていたのに
that's what I kept praying for,
どうして こんなにきつく
so tell me why I'm holding you
抱きしめているの?
so tightly in my arms?
君の声が遠くなる
Your voice is fading away
飲み込まれそうな赤。
in this red that threatens to swallow me whole.
きっと このまま君を
Surely, dissolving you just like this
溶かして夜になるだけ。
will simply turn everything to night.
淡く染まる指先に
At my faintly stained fingertips,
零れ落ちそうな赤。
is a red that seems ready to spill over.
私の中の君を奪ってしまう。
It steals away the you deep inside of me.
ちぎれていく雲間から
From the torn gaps in the clouds
溢れ出る涙。
tears overflow.
少しずつ滲む君に
Against you, blurring little by little,
ぎゅっとしがみついた。
I clung tightly.
目を閉じて 耳を塞いで
Closing my eyes and stopping up my ears,
やっと 君を閉じ込めたのに
I finally managed to lock you away inside,
繰り返してる 呼吸に混ざって
yet mixed into my repeating breaths,
少しずつ こぼれてしまいそうで
it feels like you'll spill out little by little.
いっそこのまま 誰にも届かない
I'd rather stay right here in this deep night
深い夜のここで息を止めてしまいましょう。
where no one can reach, and stop breathing forever.
遠く遠く 涙の代わりに
Far, far away, in place of tears,
正しくなるほど 疼立てる心
my heart throbs all the more as I try to be right.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know that, oh, I know it so well,
まだこんなにも 君をただこんなにも
yet even so, I still desire you this much.
口を紡いで 膝を抱えて
Keeping my lips sealed and hugging my knees,
そろそろ歩いて もういいですか
is it alright if I start walking now?
繰り返す僕の行き着く先まで
All the way to where my repeating journey leads,
私の全部に君がいた。
you were there in every part of me.
もう二度と君に触れられないこんな身体なら意味がなくて
If this body can never touch you again, it has no meaning,
今すぐにでも脱ぎ捨ててしまいたいのに
and I wish I could cast it off right this instant,
大いに藻掻いてもどうしようもなくて ひどくんだこの傷を掻きむしっている
yet no matter how much I struggle, I can't undo it, and I frantically tear at these terrible wounds.
いっそこのまま私にはいらない暗い夜の後ろで息をしてる
I'd rather just breathe behind this dark night that I no longer need.
明日なんてこのまま泣いて全部こぼれたら君を知らない私になれるのかな
If I just cried like this until tomorrow and spilled everything out, could I become someone who doesn't know you?
痛々しく涙が枯れてもこの身体中を巡りめぐるような赤
Even if my tears run painfully dry, a red color courses through my entire body.
分かっているの 分かっているのだけど
I know that, oh, I know it so well,
これじゃあまりにもこの恋があまりにもまだこんなにも君をただこんなにも
yet even so, this love is just too much, and I still want you this much...
はい、ということで、みなさん、こんあずきー！
Hi everyone, Kon-Azuki!
はい、本日は、「ルートAZKi 3Dアコースティックライブ」にお越しいただきありがとうございますー！
Thank you very much for coming to the Route AZKi 3D Acoustic Live today!
今日は右手にマイク、左手にチーズ、あなたのハートをズラゲスターということで、
Today, with a mic in my right hand and cheese in my left, I'll steal your heart...
よろしくお願いしますー！
So please look forward to it!
え、本日はお誕生日ガール、バースデーガールでございます。
Um, today I'm the birthday girl!
こちらのライブはですね、え、AZKiのアルバム『ルートエフ』を記念した、え、ライブとなりますので、
This live stream commemorates AZKi's album Route F,
本日の、え、ハッシュタグはこちら、#ルートAZKiライブ でぜひぜひ応援してくださったらとっても嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
so please support us with the hashtag #RouteAZKiLive. Thank you!
いや、いい、いい誕生日を迎えられます。ありがとうございます。
I'm having such a wonderful birthday. Thank you so much.
え、そして、え、本日はですね、アコースティックライブということで、え、生演奏、生歌唱でお届けしていくわけなんですが、え、本日、え、演奏していただきますお二人を紹介したいと思います。
Today is an acoustic live with live performances and vocals, and I'd like to introduce our musicians.
まず、アコースティックギター芦野さんー！
First, on acoustic guitar, Ashino-san!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そして、ピアノ伊藤さんー！
And on piano, Itoi-san!
ありがとうございます。というわけで、このお二人の演奏とともに、本日はアコースティックライブを、え、いっぱいね、旧曲の曲をやっていきたいと思います。よろしくお願いします！
Thank you! With their performance, we'll be playing plenty of older songs for today's acoustic live. Please enjoy!
そしてね、え、本日は最初にお届けした曲は、『エンドロールは終わらない』と、え、あ、深く、を、お届けしました。AZKiのオリジナル曲ですね。
The songs we delivered first today were Endroll wa Owaranai and Fukaku. They're AZKi's original songs.
どうでしたでしょうか？今日は、その、いつもとちょっと違う雰囲気で、え、お聞きいただけると思うので、ぜひぜひ、最後まで見てほしいなと思います。嬉しい告知もたくさんありますので、よろしくお願いします！
How was it? Today has a slightly different atmosphere, so I hope you'll watch until the end. We also have lots of exciting announcements!
7月に入りましたね！7月が入ったということで、この後は、いろんな、ちょっと夏にまつわる、え、曲を、みなさんにお届けしていこうと思いますので、ぜひぜひしっとりと、え、聞いていって戴けたらなと思います。
We've entered July! We'll be delivering various summer-related songs, so I hope you'll sit back, relax, and listen closely.
それでは、次の曲、お聞きください。『夜明けと蛍』。
Now then, please listen to the next song: Yoruakeru to Hotaru.
淡い月に見とれてしまってから
Captivated by the sight of that pale moon,
暗い足元も見えずに
I didn't even notice the dark footing below,
転んだことに気がつけないまま
Unaware that I had fallen down,
遠い夜の星が滲む
The distant stars of the night bleed through.
したいことが見つけられないから
Since I can't find what I want to do,
急いだふり俯くまま
I hurry along, keeping my head bowed down.
転んだあとに笑われてるのも気づかないふり
Pretending not to notice being laughed at after falling.
淡い月に見とれてしまうから
Entranced by the pale moon,
暗い足元も見えずに転んだことに気づけないまま
I didn't even notice when I tripped in the dark underfoot.
遠い夜の星が滲む
The distant stars of the night bleed through.
したいことが見つけられないから
Since I can't find what I really want to do,
急いだふり 俯くまま
Hurrying along with my head down,
転んだ後に笑われてるのも気づかないふりをするのだ
pretending not to notice people laughing after I trip.
形のない歌で朝を描いたままで
Just drawing the morning with a formless song,
浅い浅い夏の向こうに
far beyond the shallow, shallow summer—
冷たくない君の手のひらが見えた
I saw the palm of your hand, not even cold.
淡い空明けの蛍 自分がただの染みに見えるほど
A pale firefly at daybreak, to the point where I seem like nothing more than a stain—
嫌いなものが増えたので 地球の裏側へ飛びたいのだ
I've grown to hate so many things, I want to fly to the other side of the Earth.
無人の駅に届くまで 昨日の僕に出会うまで
Until I reach an unmanned station, until I meet yesterday's me,
胸が痛いから下を向くたびに 君がまた遠くを征くんだ
every time my heart aches and I look down, you journey far away once more.
夢を見た僕らを汚し さらば 昨夜に咲く火の花
Tainting us who dreamed, farewell, fireworks blooming in the night of yesterday.
水に映る花を花を見ていた
I was watching the flowers mirrored in the water,
水に揺るむ月を月を見ていたから
and the moon shimmering in the water, so I watched it.
夏が来ないままの空を描いたなら
If I were to paint a sky where summer never comes,
君は僕を笑うだろうか
would you laugh at me?
明け方の夢 浮かぶ月が見えた空
A dawn dream, a sky where the floating moon was visible—
朝が来ないままで 息ができたなら
if I could still breathe without morning ever coming,
遠い遠い夏の向こうへ 冷たくない 君の手のひらが見えた
far beyond the distant summer, I saw the palm of your hand, not even cold.
淡い朝焼けの夜空
A night sky of pale morning glow.
夏が来ないままの街を今 ああ 藍の色 夜明けと蛍
Now in this town where summer never comes... Ah, the indigo hue of daybreak and fireflies.
もう忘れてしまったかな 夏の木陰に座ったまま アイスを口に放り込んで 風を待っていた
Have I already forgotten? Sitting in the shade of summer, popping an ice pop into my mouth, waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな 世の中の全部嘘だらけ 本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと話したこと
Have I already forgotten? Talking about how everything in this world is full of lies, and how the two of us would go search for true value together.
忘れないように 色褪せないように 形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that I won't forget, so that it won't fade, so that material things aren't all that remains—
言葉をもっと教えて 夏が来るって教えて 僕は描いてる 目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
Teach me more words, tell me summer is coming. I am painting; what was reflected in my eyes was summer's ghost.
風にスカートが揺れて 思い出なんて忘れて 浅い呼吸をする
My skirt sways in the breeze, forgetting all memories, taking shallow breaths.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten by now,
夏の木陰に座った頃
back when we sat in the summer shade,
遠くの丘から顔を出した
a cloud peeking out from a distant hill
雲があったじゃないか
was there, wasn't it?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to reach out and grab it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
cutting through the empty sky like a fool,
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて
while I drew a single cloud on paper,
笑って握って見せて
smiling as I held it out to show you.
忘れないように
So we won't forget,
色褪せないように
so it won't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
because things left in history aren't everything.
今だけ顔も無くして
Just for now, losing even our faces,
言葉も全部忘れて
forgetting all our words as well,
君は笑っている
you are smiling,
夏を待っている僕らを往来で
as we, waiting for summer, stand on the street.
心をもっと教えて
Teach me more of your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
teach me the scent of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So we won't forget,
色褪せないように
so it won't fade away,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
because things that resonate in the heart aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
さよならだって教えて
even teach me how to say goodbye.
今も見るんだよ
Even now, I still see it,
夏に咲いている花に亡霊を
the summer ghost in the blooming flowers.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Time instead of words,
時間じゃなくて心を
heart instead of time.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat as summer approaches,
夏の匂いがする
there's the scent of summer.
There's the scent of summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten by now,
夏の木陰に座ったまま
staying seated in the summer shade,
アイスを口に放り込んで
tossing an ice pop into my mouth
風を待っていた
and waiting for the breeze.
帰り道ふざけてあるいた
We joked around on our way home,
わけもなく君を怒らせた
and I made you angry for no reason.
色んな君の顔を見たかったんだ
I guess I just wanted to see your various expressions.
大きな瞳が
Your large eyes,
泣きそうな声が
your tearful voice
今も僕の胸を締め付ける
still tighten around my chest even now.
すれ違う人の中で 君を追いかけた
In the crowd of passing strangers, I chased after you.
変わらないもの 探していた
I was searching for the things that never change.
あの日の君を忘れはしない
I will never forget how you were on that day.
時を越えてく思いがある
These feelings I have transcend time;
僕は今すぐ君に会いたい
I just want to meet you right now.
帰り道 ふざけて歩いた
We joked around on our way home.
訳もなく君を怒らせた
I made you angry for no reason.
色んな君の顔を見たかったんだ
I just wanted to see your different expressions.
大きな瞳が 泣きそうな声が
Your large eyes, your almost-crying voice,
今も僕の胸を締め付ける
Even now tighten around my heart.
すれ違う人の中で 君を追いかけた
In the crowd of strangers, I chased after you.
変わらないもの 探していた
I was searching for something that never changes.
あの日の君を 忘れはしない
I will never forget how you were on that day.
時を超えてく 思いがある
These feelings I have transcend time.
僕は今すぐ 君に会いたい
I want to meet you right now.
形ないもの 抱きしめてた
I was holding tightly to things without shape,
壊れる音も 聞こえないまま
Without even hearing the sound of them breaking.
君と歩いた 同じ道に
On the same path that we walked together,
今も灯りは 照らし続ける
Even now the light continues to shine.
変わらないもの 探していた
I was searching for something that never changes.
あの日の君を 忘れはしない
I will never forget how you were on that day.
時を超えてく 思いがある
These feelings I have transcend time.
僕は今すぐ 君に会いたい
I want to meet you right now.
はい、ありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you very much!
ということで、えー衣装も、ドレス衣装にチェンジして、
So, um, I changed into a dress outfit,
そしてね、えーステージも変わりまして、
and also, um, the stage changed,
ちょっと夜のこう庭園のステージに参りました。
and we've come to a nighttime garden stage.
ちょっとアコースティックな感じで、いいです、いいですよね。
It has an acoustic feel, which is nice, isn't it?
と言うことで、えー夜明けとホタル、花に亡霊、変わらないもの をお届けいたしました！
So, we've delivered "Yoake to Hotaru", "Hana ni Borei", and "Kawaranai Mono"!
いつもと全く雰囲気が違って、どうですか？
The atmosphere is completely different from usual, how is it?
アコースティックライブは楽しんでいただけておりますでしょうか？
Are you enjoying the acoustic live performance?
はい、そんなわけでちょっと水分補給をしつつ、
Yeah, so while I'm hydrating a bit,
素晴らしいなんか演奏が聴こえておりますけれども、
we can hear some wonderful music playing,
ということで、引き続いて、えー夏の曲をお届けして行きたいと思います。
so, I'd like to continue and deliver a summer song next.
お楽しみです、ありがと！BGM水飲みBGMがありがたいですね、ゴージャスな。
Please look forward to it—thanks! Having background music while drinking water is so nice, so gorgeous.
ゴージャスなBGMありがとうございます。
Thank you for the gorgeous BGM.
ということで、では次の曲に参りたいと思います。
With that, I'd like to move on to the next song.
それでは、次の曲をお聞きください。
Now then, please listen to the next song.
シークレットベース 君がくれたもの
"Secret Base: What You Gave Me"
secret base 〜君がくれたもの〜
[Title: secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~]
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れえない
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future, grand hopes I won't forget—
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君と夏の終わり　将来の夢
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future
大きな希望　忘れない
I won't forget my grand hopes
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
出会いは　ふとした瞬間　帰り道の交差点で
We met in a sudden moment, at an intersection on the way home
声をかけてくれたね　「一緒に帰ろう」
You called out to me, "Let's go home together"
僕は　照れくさそうに　カバンで顔を隠しながら
I hid my face shyly with my bag
本当は　とても　とても　嬉しかったよ
The truth is, I was so, so happy
ああ　花火が夜空　きれいに咲いて　ちょっと切なく
Ah, fireworks in the night sky bloom so beautifully, it's a little sad
ああ　風が時間とともに流れる
Ah, the wind flows with time
嬉しくって　楽しくって　冒険もいろいろしたね
I was so happy and fun, we had so many adventures
二人の秘密の基地の中
In our secret base
君と夏の終わり　将来の夢　大きな希望　忘れない
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future, I won't forget my grand hopes
10年後の8月　また出会えるのを　信じて
I believe we'll meet again in August 10 years from now
君が最後まで心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて笑顔でさようなら　切ないよね
Hold back your tears, say goodbye with a smile, it's so sad
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
ああ　夏休みもあと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, summer break will end soon
ああ　太陽と月　仲良くして
Ah, I hope the sun and moon make friends
悲しくって　寂しくって　喧嘩もいろいろしたね
We felt sad and lonely, we argued over many things
二人の秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base
君が最後まで心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて笑顔でさようなら　切ないよね
Hold back your tears, say goodbye with a smile, it's so sad
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
突然の転校で　どうしようもなく
Your transfer to another school was abruptly scheduled
手紙書くよ　電話もするよ　忘れないでね　僕のことを
I will write letters and give you calls, please remember me
いつまでも二人の基地の中
Forever inside our base
君と夏の終わり　ずーっと話して　夕日を見てから　星を眺め
At the end of summer with you, we kept talking, looked at the setting sun and then gazed at stars
君の頬を流れた涙はずっと忘れない
I won't forget the tears streaming down your cheeks
君が最後まで大きく手を振ってくれたこときっと忘れない
I won't forget that you kept waving your hands widely until the very end
だからこうして夢の中でずーっと永遠に...
Forever in my dream...
君と夏の終わり　将来の夢　大きな希望　忘れない
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future, I won't forget my grand hopes
10年後の8月　また出会えるのを　信じて
I believe we'll meet again in August 10 years from now
君が最後まで心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて笑顔でさようなら　切ないよね
Hold back your tears, say goodbye with a smile, it's so sad
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
いつものとおりのある日のこと　君は突然立ち上がり言った
That day was the same as any other, unexpectedly, you stood up, saying
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight"
「たまにはいいこと言うんだね」
"You come up with something good every now and then, don't ya?"
なんてみんなして言って笑った
Is the sort of thing everyone said as they laughed
明かりもない道を　バカみたいにしゃかりきに歩いた
On the path, void of light, like fools, we frolicked as we walked
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に押しつぶされないように
So that the loneliness and anxieties we carried would not squash us
いつもどおりのある日の事
Lately, things have been the same as always.
君は突然立ち上がり言った
You suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight."
「たまにはいいこと言うんだね」
"You always say such nice things sometimes."
なんてみんなして言って笑った
Everyone laughed while saying that.
明かりもない道をバカみたいにシャシャイて歩いた
We walked foolishly down a path with no light.
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に
Hugging all our loneliness and anxiety,
押し潰されないように真っ暗な世界から見上げた
so they wouldn't crush us down.
夜空は星が降るようで
The night sky was like falling stars.
いつからだろう 君のことを
I wonder when it started...
追いかける私がいた
I was the one chasing after you.
どうかがおねがい 驚かないで聞いてよ 私のこの想いを
Please don't be shocked when you hear my feelings.
「あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ」
"That's Deneb, Altair, Vega..."
君は指さす夏の大三角
You pointed out the Summer Triangle.
覚えて空を見る
I remember and look up at the sky.
やっと見つけた織姫様 だけどどこだろう彦星様
I finally found Orihime, but where is Hikoboshi?
これじゃひとりぼっち
At this rate, you'll be all alone.
楽しげなひとつ隣の君
You enjoyed yourself right by my side,
私は何も言えなくて
while I couldn't say a single thing.
本当はずっと君のことをどこかでわかっていた
The truth is, I always knew about your feelings.
見つかったって届きはしない
Even if they were found, they wouldn't reach you.
だめだよ 泣かないで
"Don't cry," I told myself.
そう言い聞かせた 強がる私は臆病で
I act tough, but I'm really a coward.
興味がないようなふりをしてた
I pretended not to care at all,
だけど胸を刺す痛みは増していく
but the pain stabbing my chest only grew.
ああそうか 好きになるってこういうことなんだね
Ah, so this is what it means to fall in love.
どうしたい?言ってごらん 心の声がする 君の隣がいい
What should I do? My heart tells me I want to be by your side.
真実は残酷だ
Reality is so cruel.
言えなかった 言えなかった
I didn't say it. I couldn't say it.
二度と戻れない あの夏の日
I'll never have that summer day back again.
きらめく星 今でも思い出せるよ
Glittering stars, I can still remember them.
笑った顔も 怒った顔も 大好きでした
Your smiling face, your angry face, I loved them all.
おかしいよね わかっていたのに
Isn't it strange? I knew it all along.
君の知らない 私だけの秘密
A secret just for me, unknown to you.
夜を越えて 遠い思い出の君が
Passing through the night, I think of you from long ago,
指をさす 無邪気な声で
pointing with your innocent voice.
言わなかった 言えなかった
With feelings I never said, couldn't say,
二度と戻れない
and will never return to again.
あの夏の日の きらめく星に
Even now, on that twinkling summer night,
今でも思い出せるよ
I can still remember it all,
笑った顔も 怒った顔も
even when I laughed or got angry.
大好きでした おかしいよね
I loved you so much. It's funny, isn't it?
わかっていたのに 君の知らない 私だけの秘密
I knew it, yet it was my own secret from you.
夜を越えて
Crossing over the night,
遠い思い出の
with your distant memories,
君が指をさす 無邪気な声で
you point with your innocent voice.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということで、SECRET BASE君がくれたもの、
And with that, um, "SECRET BASE ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~"
そして、君の知らない物語を2曲お届けいたしましたー！
and "Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari", we performed two songs!
ということで、もう後半戦に入っておりますということで、
And so, we've already entered the second half,
え、今日のアコースティックライブ、ちょっといいなって思ってくれたそこあなた！
and to everyone out there who thought today's acoustic live was nice,
え、そして、今日はね、アルバムリリース、ということで、アルバムとライブの情報をちょっとおさらいしたいと思いますー！
um, and today we're releasing an album, so I'd like to review the album and live information!
ということで、まずはアルバム情報おさらい！はい！
So first, a review of the album info! Yes!
2024年7月24日水曜日リリース、AZKi メジャー1stアルバム「Route If」が、アルバムリリースされます！よろしくお願いしますわー！
Released on Wednesday, July 24, 2024, AZKi's major 1st album "Route If" will be released! Thank you so much!
こちら通常盤で、全11曲ですね、収録した、初のビクターエンタテインメントさんに所属させていただいてからの初めてのアルバムが出ますので、ぜひぜひ
This is the regular edition, containing a total of 11 tracks. Since this is our first album since joining Victor Entertainment, please, please...
いろんな、いろんなですね、声の度の曲が入っておりますので、ぜひこちら「Route If」という文字ものこう道をここに詰め込みましたということで、
it features songs with various vocal tones, so we've packed this path called "Route If" right here,
通常盤はこちらで、そして初回限定盤にはなんと、アコースティックアレンジのDISC2が入ってなんと4曲も、アコースティックアレンジで聴けますということでこちらもよろしくお願いします！
The regular edition is here, and the first-limited edition includes DISC2 with acoustic arrangements—featuring 4 tracks in acoustic versions, so please check that out as well!
そしてそして、この夏、AZKi、ワンマンライブ開催しまーす！
And then, this summer, AZKi is holding a one-man live!
あ、ありがとうございます！2024年8月3日土曜日開催、KT Zepp横浜にて、メジャーデビューライブ「声音エントロピー」が開催されることになりました！
Ah, thank you! Held on Saturday, August 3, 2024, at KT Zepp Yokohama, our major debut live "Sound Entropy" will be held!
今日初めてAZKiのライブとか、アコースティックライブ今回見て、いいなと思ってくださりましたら、ぜひぜひ現地でお待ちしておりますので、こちらもよろしくお願いします！
If you watched AZKi's live or acoustic live for the first time today and thought it was nice, we'll be waiting for you at the venue, so please look forward to that too!
現地チケットの情報はこちら。現在、3次先行の抽選が受付中でございます。6月29日から7月7日までとなりますので、よろしくお願いします。
Here is the information for venue tickets. Currently, the 3rd advance lottery is open for applications, running from June 29 to July 7, so please check it out.
現地には行けないけど見たいなと思ってくださっているそんなあなたには、配信チケットもございますので、グッズ付きはソールドアウトしているんですが、
For those of you who can't go to the venue but want to watch, streaming tickets are also available. Although the version with goods is sold out,
配信チケットございますのでぜひぜひこちらもよろしくお願いします！そして、スケジュールはこちら。現在3次先行の会場チケットお申し込み受付しております！
streaming tickets are available, so please check those out too! And here is the schedule. Venue ticket applications for the 3rd advance are currently open!
はい。ということで今日は、そう、バースデーガールAZKiの誕生日もたくさんお祝いいただきました、ありがとうございます！
Yes. So today, well, we received so many birthday wishes for birthday girl AZKi, thank you very much!
はい、そんなわけでに、本日はアルバムリリース記念ライブということですので、
Right, so today is an album release commemorative live,
本日はアルバムの中から1曲、もう超超超最速で、新曲を1曲お披露目したいと思います！
so today, we'd like to premiere a brand new song from the album—super, super, super fast!
一体何の曲が来るのか。何の曲でしょう。
What kind of song will it be? Um, what song could it be?
10曲、11曲目はね、あの命のね2024年バーがいますけれどもち、
The 10th or 11th track, well, there's the 2024 version of "Inochi", but
今回ですね、披露させていただくのは、AZKiの大好きな大好きな、あの、柳凪さんに、作詞作曲いただきました曲をお届けしたいと思います！
yes, the one performing it this time—um, we'd like to deliver a song written and composed by AZKi's absolute favorite, Nagi Yanagi!
ということで、では、次の曲をお聞きください。「map in the cup」。
And with that, please listen to the next song: "map in the cup".
起きたてに淹れた紅茶
Freshly brewed black tea upon waking up,
朝の光お砂糖がわらに浮かべて
morning light, floating sugar on top...
起きたてに淹れた紅茶
Freshly brewed black tea upon waking up,
朝の光 お砂糖がわりに浮かべて 揺らす
floating morning light in place of sugar and swirling it,
今日のはじまりは
today's beginning is
ちょっと特別 そんな気持ちになるんだ
a bit special, that's how I feel.
温めたミルク 落とせば
If you drop in warmed milk,
カップ中に 地図みたいに広がる
it spreads like a map inside the cup,
ミニチュアの 秘密の世界旅行なんてね
a miniature secret world tour, you could say.
ゆっくり飲み干して 午後を迎えに行こうか
Let's drink it up slowly and go welcome the afternoon.
少し読み進めた本
A book I've read a little further,
降る花びら 栞のかわりに挟んで
placing falling petals inside instead of a bookmark—
きっと次に開いたら
surely when I open it next,
その香りで 物語が変わってて
the story will have changed with that scent.
少し読み進めた本
A book I've read a little further,
降る花びら 栞のかわりに挟んで
placing falling petals inside instead of a bookmark—
きっと次に開いたら
surely when I open it next,
その香りで 物語が変わってて
the story will have changed with that scent.
オレンジが滲む水面に
On the water surface where oranges bleed,
止まらない花の雨が波紋を作って
unstoppable flower rain is creating ripples—
自然の1ページ めくったら新しい季節かな
a page of nature, turning it over to a new season—
君と迎えに行こうか
shall we go welcome it together?
どんな時もずっと先の自分の話だから
Because it's always about my future self,
特別を集めて大きな束にしたいんだ一緒にね
I want to gather special things into a big bouquet together.
おやすみの前にはホットワイン
Before saying goodnight, hot wine
三日月スパイス ひとふり
with a pinch of crescent moon spice.
心をあたためて 星空見上げれば
If you warm your heart and look up at the starry sky,
どこまでも飛び立つ
flying away to anywhere,
無限大の秘密の宇宙旅行なんてね
an infinite secret space tour, you could say.
ゆっくり夢を見て 明日を迎えに行こうか
Let's dream slowly and go welcome tomorrow.
あたためて
warming it up,
星空見上げれば
looking up at the starry sky,
無限大の秘密の宇宙旅行なんてね
an infinite secret space tour, you could say.
ゆっくり夢を見て
dreaming slowly,
明日を迎えに行こうか おかえり
let's go welcome tomorrow. Welcome back.
ありがとうございました ということで 新曲いかがでしたでしょうか
Thank you very much! So, how did you like the new song?
先ほどもお伝えしましたが AZKiの大好きな大好きなアーティストである
As I mentioned earlier, it was created by Yanagi Nagi-san,
やなぎなぎさんに作っていただいた曲になります マップインザカップなんて なんかもうなんかすごくAZKiのねこう好きなね 特にこの1年は色んな変化があったんですけれど
one of my absolute favorite artists. 'map in the cup'... It has so many things I love, especially since this past year has seen all kinds of changes.
というわけで こちらの楽曲 マップインザカップに関する告知があります どうぞ
And with that, we have an announcement regarding this song, 'map in the cup'. Please take a look!
温めたミルク落とせば
If you drop in warmed milk,
カップ中に地図みたいに広がる
it spreads like a map inside the cup,
ミニチュアの秘密の世界旅行 なんてね
a miniature secret world tour, you could say.
ゆっくり飲み干して
Drink it down slowly,
午後を迎えにいこうか
and let's go greet the afternoon.
はい、ということで、え、「map in the cup」こちらですね、
So, yeah! "map in the cup"— here it is.
アルバムリリース前の7月17日水曜日0時から先行配信決定いたしました！
We've decided on an advance release starting July 17th (Wednesday) at midnight,
そして今ねちょっと流れたMVも公開予定でございますので、
And since the MV that just played is also scheduled for release,
ちょっと一足先にみんなにアルバムの曲をお届けできればと思いまして、
thinking it'd be nice to deliver the album songs to everyone just a bit early,
こちらアルバムリリース1週間前の7月17日水曜日に先行配信が決定いたしました！
we decided on an advance release one week before the album on Wednesday, July 17th!
よろしくお願いします！MVも可愛く、イラストも可愛く仕上がっておりますのでぜひよろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it! The MV and illustrations turned out so cute, so please check it out!
ということで、え、皆さんお待たせいたしました！え、本日AZKiの誕生日こちらもございます！ドン！
And with that, everyone, thanks for waiting! Today is also AZKi's birthday! Ta-da!
え、AZKi誕生日記念2024グッズでーーす！イェーイ！
AZKi Birthday Commemoration 2024 Goods! Yay!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
ありますよということで、7月1日にやっぱグッズを出したいということで、誕生日記念グッズ、え、用意してまいりました！
They're here! Since I wanted to release merch on July 1st, I prepared some birthday commemoration goods!
ということで1つ1つ、え、見ていきましょう！ね、こちらがね、えー、
So let's go through them one by one! This here, um—
なんと！ももしき先生描き下ろしのイラストとなっております！かわいい！
is an illustration drawn specially by Momoshiki-sensei! So cute!
え、今回ね、この、あの……「AZKiんちでゆっくり」をテーマに、あの、お家でリラックスできるアイテムを考えました！
And this time, the theme is "Relaxing at AZKi's House," so I thought of items you can relax with at home!
どうどうどうどうどう、かわいいかわいいかわいい！ということで、グッズを1つずつ紹介していきたいと思います！
Ta-da, so cute! So I'd like to introduce the goods one by one.
まずこちらですね、え、あずきんちアクリルジオラマスタンド！かわいい！
First is this: the AZKi's House Acrylic Diorama Stand! So cute!
買いたい人おるよ。はい、買いたい人が1、2、3（笑）。
Are there buyers out there? Yep, buyers 1, 2, 3 (laughs).
買いたいことあずきがお家でまったりしている、え、ゆっくり過ごしている1日を描いてもらいました！かわいい！
It depicts AZKi chilling and spending a relaxing day at home! So cute!
そして次！ランダムラバーキーホルダー！
And next! Random Rubber Keychain!
え、こちらですね、え、串カラス先生のファンアートでございます。「AZKiのあずきっち」シリーズが可愛くてですね、
This is fan art by Kushi Karasu-sensei. The "AZKi's Azukitchi" series is so cute,
なんと今回のために新しく描き下ろしていただきました！なんと、あずきを使ったお菓子（笑）に噴したあずきっちに注目です！
and they drew this brand new art just for this occasion! Pay attention to Azukitchi disguised as sweets made with azuki beans (laughs)!
かわいい！どれがどれ、どれ当たっても嬉しいな。あの、全部揃えたいけどランダムですが、
Cute! Whichever one you get, I'd be happy. I want to collect them all, but it's random, so please look forward to it!
え、ぜひぜひこちらもよろしくお願いします！
Please check this out as well!
そして次！あずきっちとおそろいパーカー！
And next! The Matching Hoodie with Azukitchi!
ということでパーカー作りました！
So we made a hoodie!
え、アクリルジオラマスタンドのイラストで着ているあずきりとおそろっちの、おそろっちのデザインになってますよ！わあ、嬉しい！
It has the matching design to what AZKi is wearing in the acrylic diorama stand illustration! Yay, so happy!
そしてよく見てくださいよ、この、この、このデザインを！
And look closely at this design!
え、なんと胸の、あの、この、なんだ？胸元のデザインね、胸元のデザインが、なんとAZKiの文字がマップになっているんですよ！
The chest design... the letters "AZKi" form a map! And it says "GUEST" right there.
マップになってて、そこに「GUEST」って書いてある！そして、え、この、あの持ち手のとこが、なんとゲッサーピンになっています！
And the zipper pull is a "Guesser pin"! We were very particular about these fine details.
え、そして衿の、あ、袖ですね、袖のデザインが「AZKi」ってなってて、
And the sleeve design says "AZKi",
あとね、え、フードの下バックのところを見ていただくと分かるんですけど、フードの下に、なんと開拓者が隠れてるんですね！
and if you look at the back under the hood, you can see an explorer hiding right under the hood!
これはね、ちょっとね、ここに開拓者を通わせたいと思って。めちゃくちゃおしゃれな、普段も使えるパーカーをデザインしていただきました！
I wanted explorers to feel close here. They designed a super stylish hoodie you can wear everyday!
ということでゆったり切れるフリーサイズとなっておりますので、ぜひぜひこちらゲットしてください！
It comes in a relaxed free size, so please definitely grab one!
そう、開拓者をゲストしてください（笑）。
Right, please "guest" the explorers (laughs).
そして次！あずきんちのマグカップ！
And next! AZKi's House Mug!
え、こちらも、アクリル
This is also acrylic—
ジロリネスタンドのイラストと、おそろしくちーデザインでございます。
Featuring illustrations from the glaring-eyes stand and a terrifyingly cute design!
なんと、カップを上から、上から覗きますと、
If you peek into the cup from above...
ピンガ、あるではないですかということで、
wait, there's a fingerprint right there!
えっと思って、裏もデザインして、開拓者がいて、
She wanted both front and back designed, with pioneers,
そう全部飲み干したらば、
and if you drink it all up...
あの、底の下にピンがあるということで、
um, there's a pin at the bottom,
えー、あと開拓者のシルエットデザインとなっております。
and the pioneer's silhouette is also part of the design.
はい、そして次、こちらは、
Yes, and next, this one is...
販売ボイスということで、えー、シチュエーションボイスが発売されます。
A voice set, um, a situation voice is being released!
このね、「あずきんちでゆっくりしよ」っていうテーマ、
With the theme "Let's relax at AZKi's place,"
えで、開拓者の君とゆっくり過ごすシチュエーションボイスになっております。
it's a situation voice where you spend a relaxing time with you, the pioneer.
こちらもぜひぜひよろしくお願いしますということで、
We hope you'll check this out as well!
えー、誕生日記念フルセットは、こちら！
So, the birthday commemoration full set is right here!
はい、こちらの12345点ですね。
Yes, these 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 items.
と、このフルセットをなんとか買って頂けましたらば、
And if you manage to purchase this full set,
え、チェキ風ブロマイドカードと特典ボイス、こちらが付きます！
um, a cheki-style bromide card and bonus voice will be included!
うれしい！
Yay!
ということで、直筆メッセージ書きます！
So, I will write a handwritten message!
あずき直筆メッセージやったことがなくて、今回、え、フルセット
I've never done handwritten messages as AZKi before, but this time,
全員、全員に、フルセット買ってくださった
for everyone who purchases the full set,
皆様に、え、直筆メッセージをかかせていただきますので、ぜひぜひこの初の直筆メッセージという機会なので、
I will write a handwritten message for all of you, so please, since this is a first-time opportunity,
え、ぜひフルセットご購入いただけたら嬉しいです。
I'd be so happy if you could purchase the full set.
直筆メッセージのほかに箔押しのサイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードお付いてきますので、
In addition to the handwritten message, a cheki-style bromide card with foil-stamped signature will also be included,
お見逃しなく！
so don't miss it!
そして特典ボイスもついてきますので、こちらもよろしくおねがいします！
And bonus voices are included too, so please look forward to those as well!
はい、そしてもう一つ告知させてください。こちら。
Yes, and please let me make one more announcement. Right here.
ドドン！AZKi 2018-2019 Original Songs、楽曲紹介ショート毎日投稿します！
Ta-da! AZKi 2018-2019 Original Songs: We'll be posting daily Shorts introducing songs!
明日から、明日から20日まで、最近AZKiを知ってくださった方向けに、AZKiの過去のオリジナル楽曲を紹介する試みとなっております。
Starting tomorrow until the 20th, for those who recently discovered AZKi, we have a project introducing AZKi's past original songs.
ちゃんとAZKiがね、紹介ボイスも入れているので、毎日更新していくのでショート、TikTok、え、ぜひぜひ、あの、見てみてください。
AZKi has recorded introduction voices for them, updated daily on Shorts and TikTok, so please definitely check them out.
ね、ライブも、え、あとね、1ヶ月後と迫っているので、
Also, the live is coming up in about a month,
この機会にね、そう、めちゃくちゃ用意してきたので、頑張って色々用意しているので、
so on this occasion, since I've been preparing so much and working hard on various things,
え、このね、オリジナル曲をさらっておけば、ね、もう結構前になっちゃうんですけど、え、前の曲もチェックできるということで、よろしくおねがいします！
if you review these original songs—even though they're pretty old by now—you can check out the past songs too, so please check it out!
はい、そして最後、このあと本編終了後にメンバーシップアンコールライブがございまして、え、開始は21時15分頃を予定しておりますので、ぜひぜひ、え、こちらもうろしくおねがいします！
Yes, and lastly, right after the main stream, there will be a membership encore live, scheduled to start around 21:15, so please definitely check that out as well!
今日のね、ライブよかったなって思ってくださった方はメンバーになっていただけたら嬉しいです！
If you thought today's live was great, I'd be so happy if you became a member!
ね、なんと、アルバムの曲がさらに聴けちゃうかも、ということで、よろしくおねがいします！
And hey, you might get to hear even more album songs, so please look forward to it!
いや、告知ももりもりもりだくさんということで、え、グッズも、
Lots of announcements, goods,
そしてアルバムも、ライブも、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いいたします！
and albums, and lives—please check them out!
ということで、え、きゅうきょくの、きゅうきょくめ、本編最後の曲になります。
So, the ultimate, the ultimate-th, the final song of the main part.
は、よし、じゃちょっと水を飲みまして、
Alright, let me drink some water.
水BGMありがとうございます。水BGMありがとうございます。
Thanks for the water BGM. Thanks for the water BGM.
はい、ということで、本日最後の曲をお届けしたいと思います。それではお聞きください。「命」(2024ver.)
Yes, with that, I'd like to deliver our final song of the day. Please listen. "Inochi (2024 ver.)"
息をしている だから 生きている
Breathing, therefore living.
何度も ずっと 言葉を 尽くしてきたんだ
Over and over, I've poured all my words into this.
息をしている ように 見えている
Looking as though I'm breathing.
青が染み出す 私にとっての 何か
Blue bleeding out, something special to me.
鼓動が ドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping away.
此処は いつも 変わらずに 急かし続ける
This place endlessly hurries me on, unchanged.
ボタン一つの いのち
A life at the push of a single button.
最後まで 私のこと 覚えていてくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
息をしている だから 生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I'm alive,
何度もずっと 言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
I've spent countless times pouring out words.
息をしている ように 見えている
It looks as though I'm breathing,
青が染み出す 私にとっての 何か
something bleeding blue that defines who I am.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat throbs and beats away,
此処はいつも 変わらずに 急かし続ける
and this place constantly urges me on, unchanged.
ボタン一つの いのち
a life held by a single button,
最後まで 私のこと 覚えててくれるの？
will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそう なの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm fading away, understand me, please understand!
本当のところ どうなの？ いずれは卒業するんでしょう？
What's the truth of it all? Will you eventually graduate?
日常に戻ったら 私はいなくなるの
When we return to everyday life, will I disappear?
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream that feels like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you, bye-bye.
息をしている だから 生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I'm alive,
見た目と中身の 境界線を跨いで戻って
crossing back over the boundary between appearance and reality.
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the sound stops and I can no longer move,
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll still smile at someone like me.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat throbs and beats away,
此処はいつも 変わらずに 巡り続ける
and this place endlessly keeps revolving, unchanged.
気分次第の いのち
a life driven by mere moods.
最後まで 私のこと 見届けてくれるの？
Will you watch over me until the very end?
縺れてしまいそう なの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm tangling up, understand me, please understand!
「本当の気持ち」をつないだら もう二度と戻せないのに
Once we connect our 'true feelings', there's no turning back,
君が忘れちゃったら 私はいなくなるの
so if you forget me, will I vanish?
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream that feels like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you, bye-bye.
いき急いだ あの日を
Don't lightly poke fun
軽くいじらないで あげて
at those hurried days,
それが生きる糧 になるから
because they become the nourishment of life.
大丈夫 ずっと私は 歌い続けるから
It's okay, I will keep on singing forever.
最後まで 私も生きているか 分からないけど
I don't know if I'll even be alive until the very end,
君がくれた 言葉は 確かに残ってる
but the words you gave me are certainly left behind.
最後まで 私を覚えていなくてもいいから
It's fine even if you don't remember me till the end,
いつ死んでしまうんだろう 分からない 分からないよ
when will I die? I don't know, I really don't know.
でも 今 君が笑えたこと それだけで意味があることを
But right now, the fact that you could smile—that alone gives it meaning.
君が忘れちゃっても 私は死なないから
Even if you forget, I won't die,
命のような 夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream that feels like life itself.
またね、バイバイ。
See you, bye-bye.
今日は Route AZKi のライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to the Route AZKi live today!
この Route を歩むことができてよかったんだと思える。
I feel so glad that I was able to walk this Route.
みんなのおかげだよ！
It's all thanks to everyone!
これからも一緒に開拓していこうね。
Let's keep pioneering together from now on, too!
今日は Route AZKiのライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to Route AZKi's live today!
この Route を歩むことができてよかったんだと思える。
It makes me feel so glad I was able to walk this Route.
みんなのおかげだよ！
It's all thanks to everyone!
これからも一緒に開拓していこうね。
Let's keep pioneering together from now on too.
AZKi ♡